<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>The linkage between technology and art</title>
    <link href="/2022/10/08/The-linkage-between-technology-and-art/"/>
    <url>/2022/10/08/The-linkage-between-technology-and-art/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Now that more and more artists are also creating digitally, with many of their works existing purely on the screen, digital art is becoming one of the most valued art forms of our time. With the introduction of NFT, the art world is rapidly changing.</p><p>When I first saw Beeple’s work “Everyday: The First 5000 Days”, I was shocked. I was more shocked as I knew that it was sold for $69.3 million worth non-fungible token (NFT). It was just paintings at first, but later Beeple began to incorporate abstract themes, color, form and repetition.Over the past five years, the work has become more relevant to the current times and responsive to current events.</p><p>The emerging technology has changed our perception towards artwork significantly. Especially,VR.</p><p>Virtual reality does more than only make it easier for people to express themselves artistically. Because it is multidimensional, it also enhances the aesthetic experience.</p><p>Virtual reality allows users to be part of a piece of art, immersed by art. It allows users to enter an entirely different space where they can view from numerous perspectives rather than just one. With VR, we are able to experience other people’s humanity.</p><p>But it also raises a lot of questions: Is VR a way of manipulating human emotions? How long can empathy last after the VR experience?I think VR can evoke empathy, but it doesn’t make users think from other people’s perspectives. People still need to rely on their own imaginations to construct the experiences of others. </p><p>The mechanism of VR reminds me of the artist Alexa Meade. She does portraits which are painted on the human body and put upon colored backdrops, transform real persons into a flat surface and appear to be 2D pieces of art. The way she chooses to do the opposite of that VR is doing also provides an interesting perspective to think about VR.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Installation of memory</title>
    <link href="/2022/10/01/Installation-of-memory/"/>
    <url>/2022/10/01/Installation-of-memory/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Installation Waste Not by Song Dong offers me a fresh way of perceiving memories. He displays over 10,000 items from his mother’s decades-long collection. The artifacts serve as a means of remembering. It revisits the memories of a specific family living in a politically unstable era. The work elicits strong emotions via the rediscovery of intimated objects Song Dong’s mother collected, all of which retain memories.</p><p>Personal objects from Song Dong’s installation not only preserve memory but also feelings and experiences at the time. This rekindling of past experiences and emotions reminds me of this creative repository we are building now. By writing down and organizing the things we see and learn each day in life or class, we can always go back and look at what inspires us and  influences our art-making process.</p><p>My work is always related to memory. I explore the theme in my writing, my photographs, and my video work.  Different means of approaches reveal the topic differently. From my perspective, memory is an abstract and floating mind, which can’t be truly stored the way it was. But Song Dong’s installation transforms this abstraction into specific objects. It inspires me to think memory’s  characteristic as an attachment to certain objects.</p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
